Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski. On this podcast, I help
coaches and mentors make more money in
their business. I want to talk about
what's working right now in the space of
webinars. You know, we've been doing
webinars for a long time. I think gone
of the days though of the 90 minute or
120 minute webinar. I look for doing
things that are under
30 minutes long. And the reason why is
because people's attention span is
shorter than ever. It's been blasted by
social media and Tik Tok and all these
things that we have access to that
people want instant gratification and
answers to the questions that they're
looking for. In fact, you right now
listening to this if I wasn't giving you
strategies within the first minute
probably would have clicked off of this
video right here. And so what we're
going to do is we're going to break down
for you what can you actually do in 30
minutes and the purpose of it. Now the
purpose of any kind of webinar that you
offer, a lot of people have this
misconstrued. It's not to provide
transformation to people. It's not to
coach people. It's to be a first test to
taste what you have to offer. Uh it's a
it's like a taste tester of working with
you. So is your YouTube content. So is
your your social media content is kind
of more grab the attention and get a
follower. But when it comes to like a
long form content that's under 30
minutes long, but maybe it's over 10 to
15 minutes long. Um, the purpose behind
that is for sales
and
marketing. The only reason why I do this
podcast, the only reason why I make
videos on my YouTube is for sales and
marketing. The only reason why I do
webinars is for sales and marketing.
What am I marketing? I'm marketing my
mentorship program, my membership. my
membership. I give people a 14-day free
trial to be able to join into it. And
and again, this isn't going to be a
sales pitch for that. But what I'm
talking about is is that our best way of
marketing people into those is with some
form of a 30inut training. So, how does
that exactly work? What does that look
like? Well, it looks something like
this. People will find online, whether
it be through my organic content or an
advertisement, a page that has an offer.
And this is an offer page right here.
This is not the 30-minute video. This is
just a little 30 second intro right
here. And this is all about running uh
Instagram ads. We have another one right
here. We're we're about to launch real
soon. Uh it's a 30 minute class. Get
thousand subscribers in 30 minutes. The
art of lead Getting. Turn your email
list into a client generating machine.
Okay. So, the purpose behind this
is to be able to
capture leads because we're providing
value. We're teaching something. But
then once we capture the leads, people
then go in over and then they watch a 30
minute training, some kind of a video
training with me where I'm going to
break down a concept. I'm going to go
over the details of those concepts. And
then in this I get to talk about what I
have to offer. I get to talk about what
I am selling to people. So this breaks
down
very simply and there's a format that I
always follow that we do for this.
Number one, it's usually broken down
into three segments. The very first
segment, what we're going to do is we're
going to get people hyped up. We're
going to get them really excited about
what it is that we're that we're talking
about, what it is that we're offering.
And if somebody gives you their name and
email address to sign up, even if
they're already on your email list, by
the way, you want to hype them up in the
beginning right here for the outcome of
the training itself. Now, in a 30-minute
training, the only part that's actually
going to probably be practical training
is going to be in the middle here, which
is about the middle 15 minutes. And this
is where you're going to go over the
practical aspects of what they signed up
for. So, we got the hype up. We have the
vision casting. And listen, I before you
say, "Well, I don't want to do that. I
don't want to hype people up. I just
want to give value. Can I tell you
something?
I used to be that way as well. I was a
person who was just like, I just want to
give value. I just want to and it made
me zero dollars in my business. And so
if you want to make zero dollars in your
business, do a bunch of work that
doesn't work. Um, just keep giving
value. Okay? Just keep giving value.
Make nothing. And that's and I don't
mean to be cocky here, but that that's
the case after working with thousands of
people in the industry. I've been in
this online coaching and mentoring space
for 22 years, is that if you just give
value, just give value, you're not going
to make any money. So there's actually a
strategic cadence for how to
communicate, how to talk, and the right
people are going to resonate with it.
The wrong ones are not going to. It's
going to repel the wrong ones. So in the
opening portion, you want to cast
vision. You want to talk about what are
the mental foundations to get the result
that you're going to be talking about in
the practical aspect.
You also want to soft mention what you
have for sale in the beginning. I do
this even in every single YouTube video
that I do. I already did it in this one.
I mention that I have a coaching
program, that I have a membership, that
I have a 14-day trial to it. I just
mentioned it a second time. See what I'm
saying? And so within the first five
minutes, I've already mentioned what it
is that I have to offer to people. I'm
just soft mentioning it. I'm not trying
to bait and switch anybody. I make it
very clear what my intentions are. And
so that's what you want to do is you
want to make it very clear what your
intentions are. And then you go into
those practical aspects of how to
actually get that result that they're
looking for. This is the teaching
portion. This is where you share and you
teach and you cover exactly what people
are looking for. This is the format that
works for our webinars. And then the
last part right here, this is your sales
pitch. And before you say, you know,
sales is a is a is a four-letter dirty
word. It's actually five letters, but
before you say sales is a dirty word,
it's not. What we do is that if somebody
gets to the end of the webinar, if
somebody gets to the end of the
30-minute webinar and they opted in and
they signed up for it, chances are they
want to buy what you have to offer or
they wouldn't even be there. they would
have clicked off. They would have left
already. And we have the data for this.
If I put
5,000 people through a webinar or 500 or
50, the numbers are still the same. That
only about 25 to 30% of people are going
to make it all the way to the sales
pitch part. And those are our most
qualified group of people. The the other
60 to 70% of people, 75%, they dropped
off in the middle part. They got what
they wanted and they left. and they
weren't they had no intention of staying
through till the end. They weren't
looking for help for anything. And so
understand again, you're in business to
make money. You're in business to
produce a financial result for yourself.
And so because of that, it's important
to sell. And so the way that we sell is
at the end of our webinar, you can kind
of see how I do it right here in this
one right here, is I actually just share
my screen on screen and I talk about my
offer. I talk about my coaching program,
the Wealthy Coach Academy program, and I
go over the details of it. Right now,
it's on a waiting list. If you do want
more info on that, you can find a link
in the description below that will
actually give you info to kind of get a
backdoor access on how to get in and get
a 14-day trial to jump in with us. But
even then,
people aren't going to just sign up for
that. So, you also then have to have
follow-up emails. You want to make sure
that you are following up with the
person. Following up to remind them of
the webinar that they went through,
which again, most people are not even
going to go through the webinar they
signed up for. So, you want to remind
them of the thing they signed up for.
You got to remind them of your offer.
And we're not se we're not spending a
bunch of effort segmenting out people
based on okay did they watch it or did
they not. We're not going to tell them
about the offer or anything like that.
No, we're not we're not spending a bunch
of time and energy doing that. Our goal
is simply to expose people to our offer
and what we have. Whether they buy or
not, they will buy eventually. They will
come in. That's what the data shows is
that if we just continuously expose our
offer to people and tell them what we
have for sale, not our information only,
we share our information as a gateway to
give us an opportunity to talk about
what we have for sale. And I see a lot
of amateur coaches and mentors, they
won't do this. They're not using it as
that gateway. They're afraid to they're
afraid of bothering people or pissing
people off or whatever these things that
we tell ourselves that we don't want to
happen. This we're afraid of
disappointing people or discou we're
we're afraid of whatever that fear is.
Stop letting fear run your life in your
business, my friends,
and start making some money. Start doing
what is effective. Start doing what the
most effective mentors and coaches do
and start to see results. So, you got
your follow-up emails, you got your
webinar. You would follow this
three-step sequence in the webinar.
Having your energy in the right place is
a good thing. Being excited, but not
overly excited,
you know, being confident is important
and that's what leads people to become
your client. We find that these are the
most effective ways to get clients for
coaching and online course businesses.
Um, you know, there's a lot of different
opt-in offers you could do. You could do
a mini course. Those work as well. Mini
courses are pretty good. Um, they're
essentially the same thing. They're just
broken down into multiple segments,
especially if it's a paid miniourse.
Those work really well. If people are
paying for this type of offer, even if
it's just like seven bucks or 17 bucks,
they are more likely to be committed to
buy whatever your bigger paid offer is
in the end if they're paying for the
webinar. And yes, it is a sales pitch.
Yes, the purpose behind it is to sell
them.
The way you want to do it is you want to
do it to where it doesn't feel like a
sales pitch. And this is why we do this
three-step sequence. You start with
building up excitement. You deliver the
practical goods, but you don't give so
much
that people are like, "Well, I got
everything and then I'm done." You want
to seed the idea that you could take it
so much further. And that's when you
give your call to action. And that's
when I just I just share the screen on
my computer and I go down the page and I
just start reading what's on the page. I
show the testimonies. I show all the
details and I walk people through how to
purchase and how to become a client. And
that is what has gotten us clients and
built our business to seven figures. And
that can work for you as well. Listen,
I'd love to have you jump in with us in
our in one of our programs and be become
a client of ours. It's a great uh
community. We have incredible coaches in
it. We have hundreds of coaches in our
community and we're getting them results
every single week. And I want to help
get you results as well. I'd love to see
you in there. Jump in now. Try it out.
Go check the link below to get more
info. We'll talk soon.
[Music]
[Applause]